Guide to the Wesley C. Salmon Papers, 1950-2003 ASP.2003.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Manuscripts, 1957-2001; 1960-2001; II.
  - Article Manuscripts, 1965-2001; 2.
    - "Deductivism Visited and Revisited", 1984-1988 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - "Determinism and Indeterminism in Modern Science", 1970-1971 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - "Discussion: Reply to Kyburg", 1965 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - "Dynamic Rationality", 1986-1988 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - "Dynamic Rationalitiy, 1986-1988 (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - "Empiricism: The Key Question", 1983-1984 (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - "Empirical Statements About the Absolute", 1964 (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - "Encounter with David Hume", 1972-1975 (Box 38, Folder 16)
    - "'Exists' as a Predicate", 1957 (Box 38, Folder 17)
    - "Experimental Atheism", 1978 (Box 38, Folder 18)
    - "Explaining Things Probabilistically", 2001 (Box 38, Folder 19)
    - "Explanation", 1978-1981 (Box 38, Folder 20)
    - "Explanation: Blackwell Companion", 1991 (Box 38, Folder 21)
    - "Explanation and Confirmation", 2000 (Box 38, Folder 22)
    - "Explanation and Relevance", 1970 (Box 38, Folder 23)
    - "Explanation in Archaeology: An Update", 1988-1992 (Box 38, Folder 24)
    - "Explanation, Theories of", 1994 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - "Explanatoriness: Cause versus Craig", 1999-2000 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Figures, undated (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - "Formulation of Why Questions", 1985 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - "Foundations of Scientific Inference", 1966 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - "Frequency Interpretation and Antecedent Probabilities", 1953 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - "Frequency Interpretation and Antecedent Probabilities", 1953 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - "Friedman on Explanation", 1986-1987 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - "Functional Explanation", 1978 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - "Fundamental Problems in the Concept of Randomness", 1972 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - "Further Reflections", 1981 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - "Geometry", undated (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - "Grunbaum Festschrift", 1982 (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - "Hans Reichenbachs Lebeh Und Die Tragweite Seiner Philosophie", 1975 (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - "Hans Reichenbach: Logical Empiricist: Preface", 1977 (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - "Han Reichenbach's Vindication of Induction", 1989-1991 (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - "Hempel, Carnap, and Reichenbach on Scientific Realism", 1991-1992 (Box 39, Folder 17)
    - "Hempel's Conception of Inductive Inference in Inductive Statistical Explanation", 1977 (Box 39, Folder 18)
    - "Hempel: Epilogue", 1979 (Box 39, Folder 19)
    - "Hempel: Obituary", 1997 (Box 39, Folder 20)
    - "Hempel on the Rationality of Science", 1983 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - "In Memoriam: Grover Maxwell", 1981-1991 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - "In Memoriam: J. Alberto Coffa", 1985 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - "In Praise of Relevance", 1981 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - "Indeterminism and Epistemic Relativization", 1977 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - "Induction and Language", 1961 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - "Induction, Causation, and Scientific Explanation", 1967 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - "Inductive Fallacy", 1979 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - "Inductive Inference", 1963 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - "Induction and Intuition.", 1967-1969 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - "Inference to the Best Explanation", 1996-1999 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - "Informal Analytic Approaches to the Philosophy of Science", 1978 (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - "Informal Reasoning and Formal Rules", 1991 (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - "Inquires Into the Foundations of Science", 1968 (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - "Intuitions-Good and Not-so-Good", 1988 (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - "Intuitions: Italian Version", 1986 (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - "Inverse Inference", undated (Box 40, Folder 17)
    - "John Venn's Logic of Chance", 1980 (Box 40, Folder 18)
    - "Justification of Inductive Rules of Inference", 1968 (Box 40, Folder 19)
    - Koner Series, 1970-1976 (Box 40, Folder 20)
    - "Law, In Science", 1971 (Box 40, Folder 21)
    - "Letter to the Editor", 1964 (Box 40, Folder 23)
      - "Laws, Modalities, and Counterfactuals", 1977 (Box 40, Folder 22)
    - "Logic", 1972 (Box 40, Folder 24)
    - "Logic Reference Notes", 1958 (Box 40, Folder 25)
    - "Logical Empiricism", 1999 (Box 40, Folder 26)
    - "Mathematical Magic Show", 1977 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - "Memory and Perception in Human Knowledge", 1972 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - "Methodology", undated (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - "Miracle of Miniaturization", 1986 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Misc. Notes and Jottings, undated (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - "Modern Analysis of the Design Argument", 1951 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - "Moral Responsibility in the Emotive Theory of Value", 1953-1989 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - "Natural Science, Epistemology of, undated (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - "Nichtdeduktive Argumentationsformen", 1999 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - "Note on Russell's Anticipations", 1975 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - "Note on the Hyothetico-Deductive Method", undated (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - "Numerals vs. Numbers", 1973 (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - "Objective Probabilities", 1957 (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - "Objective Homogeneity of Reference Classes", 1977 (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - "On the Alleged Temporal Anisotropy of Explanation", 1991 (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - "On Vindicating Induction and Reply to Black", 1963 (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - "Ontological Proof for Null Set", 1977 (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - "Ornithology in a Cubical World: Reichenbach on Scientific Realism", 1999 (Box 41, Folder 18)
    - "Partial Entailment as a Basis for Inductive Logic", 1969 (Box 41, Folder 19)
    - "Perception and Memory", 1953 (Box 41, Folder 20)
    - Philosopher's Index, 1977-1979 (Box 41, Folder 21)
    - "Philosopher in a Physics Course", 1977-1983 (Box 41, Folder 22)
    - "Philosophical Significance of One Way Speed of Light", 1977 (Box 41, Folder 23)
    - "Philosophy and the Rise of Modern Science", 1990 (Box 41, Folder 24)
    - "Philosophy of Hans Reichenbach", 1977 (Box 41, Folder 25)
    - "Philosophy of Logic", undated (Box 41, Folder 26)
    - "Plausibility Arguments in Science", undated (Box 41, Folder 27)
    - "La Prediction Rationnelle", undated (Box 41, Folder 28)
    - "Predictive Inference", 1957 (Box 41, Folder 29)
    - "Principle of the Common Cause", 1977 (Box 41, Folder 30)
    - "Production of Induction", 1966 (Box 41, Folder 31)
    - "Probabilistic Causality", 1980 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - "Probabilistic Explanation: Introduction", 1982 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - "Problem of Induction", undated (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - "Projectability", undated (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - "Propensities: A Discussion Review", 1971 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - "Propensioni Causali", 1988-1990 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - "Propensioni Causali", 1990 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - "Psychoanalytic Theory and Evidence", 1959 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - "Publications: An Annotated Bibliography", 1988 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - "Quasars, Causality, and Geometry", 1993 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - "Quasars: Letter to the Editor", 1991 (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Questia, 2001 (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - "Reason in Revolution: A Study of Theory- Change in Science", 1997 (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - "Ragionamento Informale e Regole Formali", 1991 (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - "Rationality and Objectivity in Science", 1987 (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - "Rationality and Objectivity in Science", 1987 (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - "Rational Prediction", 1980-1981 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - "Rational Prediction", 1980-1981 (Box 43, Folder 1 B)
    - "Razionalita e Oggettivita Nella Scienza ovvero Tom Kuhn Incontra Tom Bayes", 1988 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - "Realistic Account of Causation", 2000 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - "Realistic Account of Causation", 2000 (Box 43, Folder 3 B)
    - "Reflections of a Bashful Bayesian", undated (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - "Regular Rules of Induction", 1956 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - "Reichenbach, Hans: Cambridge Dictionary, ", undated (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - "Reichenbach, Hans: Cambridge Dictionary, ", undated (Box 43, Folder 6 B)
    - "Reichenbach, Hans: Companion to Epistemology", 1992 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - "Reichenbach, Hans: Companion to Metaphysics", undated (Box 43, Folder 7 B)
    - "Reichenbach, Hans: Dictionary of American Biography", 1974-1976 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - "Reichenbach, Hans: Routledge Encyclopedia", 1993-1996 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - "Reichenbach, Hans: Routledge Encyclopedia", 1993-1996 (Box 43, Folder 9 B)
    - "Reichenbach Memoir: Preface", 1977 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - "Reichenbach Memoir: Preface", 1977 (Box 43, Folder 10 B)
    - "Reichenbach on Realism", undated (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - "Religion and Science: A New Look at Hume's Dialogues", 1978 (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - "Reply to Efron", 1973 (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - "Reply to Lehman", 1973 (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - "Reply to Pettijohn", 1956 (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - "Response to 'Toward a Theory of the Process of Explanation'", 1999 (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - Review: "Barker's Induction and Hypothesis", 1959 (Box 43, Folder 18)
    - Review: "Carnap's Philosophical Foundations of Physics", 1966-1967 (Box 43, Folder 19)
    - Review: "Colodny's Frontiers of Science and Philosophy", 1963-1964 (Box 43, Folder 20)
    - Review: "Culberton's Mathematics and Logic for Digital Devices", 1958 (Box 43, Folder 21)
    - Review: "Day's Inductive Probability" (Box 43, Folder 22)
    - Review: "Destouches's Physico-logical Problems", 1960 (Box 43, Folder 23)
    - Review: "Earman's Bayes or Bust", 1992-1999 (Box 43, Folder 24)
    - Review: "Elkana's Interaction Between Science and Philosophy", 1974 (Box 43, Folder 25)
    - Review: "Good's Acausalcalculus", 1963 (Box 43, Folder 26)
    - Review: "Grunbaum's Modern Science and Zeno's Paradoxes", 1970 (Box 43, Folder 27)
    - Review: "Grunbaum's Philosophical Problems of Space and Time", 1963-1965 (Box 43, Folder 28)
    - Review: "Grunbaum's Philosophical Problems of Space and Time Second Edition", 1974-1975 (Box 43, Folder 29)
    - Review: "Harre, Greenwood and Smith", 1960-1962 (Box 43, Folder 30)
    - Review: "Jeffrey's Scientific Inference", 1957 (Box 43, Folder 31)
    - Review: "Kyburg's Probability and the Logic of Rational Belief", 1967 (Box 43, Folder 32)
    - Review: "Lachman's Foundation of Science", 1957 (Box 43, Folder 33)
    - Review: "Meehl", undated (Box 43, Folder 34)
    - Review: "Pera's Ambiguous Frog", 1992-1994 (Box 43, Folder 35)
    - Review: "Reichenbach's Modern Philosophy of Science", 1960 (Box 43, Folder 36)
    - Review: "Reichenbach's Philosophy of Space and Time", 1960 (Box 43, Folder 37)
    - Review: "Turnebohm's Logics for Quantum Mechanics", 1959 (Box 43, Folder 38)
    - Review: "Von Mises's Probability, Statistics, and Truth", 1959 (Box 43, Folder 39)
    - Review: "Von Wright's The Logical Problem of Induction", 1959 (Box 43, Folder 40)
    - "Robert Leslie Ellis and The Frequency Theory", 1980 (Box 43, Folder 41)
    - "Russell on Scientific Inference", 1974 (Box 43, Folder 42)
    - "S-R Model of Scientific Explanation", 1975-1976 (Box 43, Folder 43)
    - "Salmon for Ehrlich", undated (Box 43, Folder 44)
    - Schrodinger Translation, 1972-1974 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - "Science and Human Understanding", 1991-1995 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - "Science and Sorcery", undated (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - "Scientific Explanation and the Casual Structures of the World", 1993 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - "Scientific Explanation: Causation and Unification", 1990 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - "Scientific Explanation: Consensus or Progress", 1986 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - "Scientific Explanation: Three Basic Conceptions", 1984 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - "Scientific Understanding in the Twentieth Century", 2001 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - "Short Run", 1955 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - "Should We Attempt to Justify Induction", 1957 (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - "Size of Astronomical Objects", 1974 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - "Sizes of Celestial Bodies: A Hole in the Argument", 1982-1990 (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - "Spirit of Logical Empiricism", 1998 (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - "Statistical Explanation: Companion to the Philosophy of Science", 1993 (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - "Statistical Explanation", 1965 (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - "Statistical Explanation and Its Model", 1984 (Box 44, Folder 16)
    - "Statistical Prediction", undated (Box 44, Folder 17)
    - "Status of Prior Probabilities in Statistical Explanation", 1965 (Box 44, Folder 18)
    - "Theoretical Explanation", 1975 (Box 44, Folder 19)
    - "Theoretical Term", undated (Box 44, Folder 20)
    - "Theory", undated (Box 21)
    - "Third Dogma of Empiricism", 1977 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - "Twin Sisters: Philosophy and Geometry", 1980 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - "Unfinished Business: The Problem of Induction", 1978 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - "Uniformity of Nature", 1953 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - "Use, Mention, and Linguistic Invariance", 1966 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - "Value of Scientific Understanding", 1993 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - "Van Fraassen on Explanation", 1987 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - "Verifiability and Logic", 1966 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - "Vindication of Induction", 1961 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - "Wissenschaft, Grundlagen Der", 1976-1980 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - "What Happens in the Long Run?", 1965 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - "What is Scientific Explanation", 1976 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - "What is Scientific Explanation", 1976 (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - "What? Where? When? Why?" (Box 45, Folder 12-14)
    - "Why Ask Why", 1978 (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - "Who Needs Inductive Acceptance Rules", 1968 (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - "Zeno of Elea", undated (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - "Zenoesque Problem", 1971 (Box 45, Folder 18)
    - "Zentrablatt Fur Mathematik", 1975 (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - Articles Dedicated to Salmon, 1965-2001; 3.
    - "Causality and Explanation", 2003 (Box 45, Folder 20)
    - "Reflections on Structuralism and Scientific Explanation", 2002 (Box 45, Folder 21)
    - "Is There a Valid Experimental Argument for Scientific Realism", 2002 (Box 45, Folder 22)
    - "Real Realism: The Galilean Strategy", 2001 (Box 45, Folder 23)
- Professional Talks, 1970-2001; III.
  This series contains the outlines of lectures, the manuscripts of lectures, and the typescripts of lectures and talks given to professional audiences at institutions other than Salmon's home university. The lectures were given at professional conferences and at other universities and colleges.
  - 1972-1973 Lectures (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - "Aims of Science": Physics Department, 1981 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - "Alternative Models of Scientific Explanation": Grasshopper, 1977 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - "Appraisal of Theories": PSA Symposium, 1990 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - "Are Explanations Arguments?" Minnesota Center, 1974 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - "Avogadro's Number": Analytical Chemistry Forum, 1982 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - "Carnap Paper": APA Eastern, 1967 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - "Carnap Paper": APA Eastern, 1967 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - "Causal Concepts in Various Sciences": UBC, 1980 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - "Causal Explanation in Archaeology": Theoretical Archaeology Conference, 1980 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - "Causal Propensities": Pittsburgh and Mt. St. Marys, 1990 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - "Causal Structure of the World": UCLA, 2001 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - "Causal versus Noncausal Explanation": University of Coruna, 2001 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - "Causation in Scientific Explanation": USC, 1977 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - "Causation in Scientific Explanation": Oberlin Colloquium, 1977 (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - "Causation: A Realistic Approach": Indiana University, 2000 (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - "Causality": Universidad Nacional de Catamarca, 1994 (Box 46, Folder 17)
  - "La Causalita": Center Fiorentino, 1993 (Box 46, Folder 18)
  - "La Causalita": University of Genova, 1998 (Box 46, Folder 19)
  - "Causality and Explanation": University of Minnesota Workshop, 1985-1986 (Box 46, Folder 20)
  - "Causality and Explanation": University of Minnesota Workshop, 1985-1986 (Box 46, Folder 20 B)
  - "Causality, Geometry, and Quasars": University of Trieste, 1993 (Box 46, Folder 21)
  - "Causality and Medicine": DLMPS Congress, 1995 (Box 46, Folder 22)
  - "Causality and Naturalism": NEH Summer Institute on Naturalism, 1993 (Box 46, Folder 23)
  - "Causality, Probability, and Indeterminism": Fetzer NEH Institute, 1988 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - "Causality: Production and Propagation": University of British Columbia, 1979 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - "Causality: Production and Propagation": PSA Symposium, 1980 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - "Causality Without Counterfactuals": University of Virginia and University of Pittsburgh, 1994 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - "Clocks and Simultaneity": DePauw University and Indiana University, 1972 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - "Clocks and Simultaneity in Special Relativity": Ohio State University, 1973 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - "Comets, Pollen, and Dreams: Some Reflections on Scientific Explanation": University of New Hampshire, 1975 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - "Comets, Pollen, and Dreams: Some Reflections on Scientific Explanation": University of New Hampshire, 1975 (Box 47, Folder 7 B)
  - "Comets, Pollen, and Dreams": Hope College, 1979 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - "Comets, Pollen, and Dreams": University of Notre Dame, 1981 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - "Comets, Pollen, and Dreams": Lafayette College, 1982 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - "Comets, Pollen, and Dreams": University of Alabama in Birmingham, 1982 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - "Comets, Pollen, and Dreams": University of Miami, 1982 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - "Commentary: Leaves from an HPS Songbook": HPS 25th Anniversary Celebration, 1985 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - "Comment on Bas Van Fraasssen's 'What are the Laws of Nature'": Scientific Realism Workshop, 1985 (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - "Comment on Byerly's 'Placebo Effect'", 1973-1974 (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - "Comment on Glymour's 'Explanations, Tests, Unity, and Necessity'": APA Western Division Conference, 1980 (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - "Comment on Glymour's 'Theory and Evidence'": Conference on Confirmation, 1980 (Box 47, Folder 17)
  - "Comment on Hertzberg", 1973 (Box 47, Folder 18)
  - "Comment on J. Plato's 'Probabilistic Causality from A Dynamic Point of View'": Center Conference, 1989 (Box 47, Folder 19)
  - "Comment on Madden": Harvard, 1957 (Box 47, Folder 20)
  - "Comment on Martin": APA Western Division Conference, 1968 (Box 47, Folder 21)
  - "Comment on Maxwell": Russell Conference, 1972 (Box 47, Folder 22)
  - "Comment on Parrini and Muhlholzer": Pittsburgh-Konstanz Colloquium, 1991 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - "Comment on Paul Fitzgerald's 'Time out of Mind'": APA Western Division Conference, 1982 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - "Comment on Scheibe's 'A Synthetic Theory of Reduction in Physics'": Grunbaum Colloquium, 1990 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - "Comment on Schlesinger and Grunbaum": AAAS, 1963 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - "Comment on Sober's 'The Principle of the Common Cause'": Chapel Hill Colloquium in Philosophy, 1987 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - "Comment on Vincent Smith's 'What Instances Instantiate'": APA Eastern Division Conference, 1968 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - "Commit It Then to the Flames": Florence, 1999 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - "Concept of Inductive Evidence": Rochester, undated (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - "Confirmation and Relevance": Boston Colloquium, 1972 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - "Conflicting Conceptions of Scientific Explanation": APA Eastern Conference, 1985 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - "Connections Among Events": University of Trieste, 1996 (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - "Constructive Empiricism": Method and the Exchange of Knowledge in Science Conference, 1990 (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - "Contemporary Look at Zeno's Paradoxes", undated (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - "Creation and Science": ACLU Deposition, 1982 (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - "Design Argument": Hume Bicentennial Conference, 1976 (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - "Determinism and Explanation": Rice University, undated (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - "Discussion": Conference on Absolute and Relational Theories of Space and Space Time, 1974 (Box 48, Folder 17)
  - "Discussion on Philosophical Lessons from Quantum Theory": University of Notre Dame, 1987 (Box 48, Folder 18)
  - "Discussion: Scientific Explanation": Experience Reality and Scientific Explanation Workshop, 1996 (Box 48, Folder 19)
  - "Doubting Thomas and Cross Bearing": University of Alabama ay Birmingham, 1997 (Box 48, Folder 20)
  - "Dreams of a Famous Physicist": Western Kentucky University and Castiglioncello Conference, 1996 (Box 48, Folder 21)
  - "Dreams of a Famous Physicist": University of Pittsburgh Physics Club, 1998 (Box 48, Folder 22)
  - "Empiricism; The Key Question": Arizona State University and University of Pittsburgh, 1983 (Box 48, Folder 23)
  - "Encounter with David Hume": Richard Gale's Class, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 24)
  - "Explaining Remarkable Coincidences": University of California Irvine, 1982 (Box 48, Folder 25)
  - "Explaining Remarkable Coincidences": University of Virginia, 1982 (Box 48, Folder 26)
  - "Explanation in Archaeology: An Update": Archaeological Theory and Method Symposium, 1988 (Box 48, Folder 27)
  - "Fingarette Introduction": APA Pacific Division, 1977 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - "Flight of Time": Montana State University and University of California Santa Cruz, 1983 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - "Formulation of Why Questions": Society of American Archaeologists Annual Meeting, 1983 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - "Foundational Studies of Science", undated (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - "Four Decades of Scientific Explanation": University of Bologna, 1988 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - "Four Decades of Scientific Explanation": University of Bologna, 1988 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - "Galileo Galilei", 1990 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - "Hempel, Carnap, and Reichenbach on Scientific Realism": Carnap-Reichenbach Centennial, 1991 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - "Hempel on the Rationality of Science": APA Eastern Division Conference, 1983 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - "History of Statistical Explanation": Minnesota Center Seminar, undated (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - "History of Statistical Explanation": Minnesota Center Seminar, undated (Box 49, Folder 10 B)
  - "Humanities Education in a Technological Age": Academic Leadership Conference, 1985 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - "Inference to the Best Explanation": Leipzig Workshop, 1996 (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - "Inference to the Best Explanation": Haifa Conference and Bologna Seminar, 1998 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - "Importance of Scientific Understanding": Amherst College, 1988 (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - "Informal Analytic Approaches": PSA Research Problems Conference, 1977 (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - "Induction: A Defense", undated (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - "Induction/Probability and Causation/Explanation": University of Pittsburgh, 2000 (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - "Inductive Explanation", undated (Box 49, Folder 18)
  - "Inductive Inference in Science": Pittsburgh Lectures, 1964 (Box 49, Folder 19)
  - "Inductive Inference and Statistical Explanation": DLMPS International Conference, 1975 (Box 49, Folder 20)
  - "Intellectual Autobiography", undated (Box 49, Folder 21)
  - "Intuitions-Good and Not-so-Good": National Science Foundation Conference on Probability and Causation, 1985 (Box 49, Folder 22)
  - "Italian Round Table", 1999 (Box 49, Folder 23)
  - "Jose Alberto Coffa": Coffa Memorial, 1985 (Box 49, Folder 24)
  - Keynote Lecture: Air Force Science Seminar, 1968 (Box 49, Folder 25)
  - Lectures: Australia, 1978 (Box 49, Folder 26)
  - "Lecture on Quasar System and Statistical Hypothesis": Conference on Applications of Inductive Logic, 1978 (Box 49, Folder 27)
  - "Looking at Causality in a Different Way": University of British Columbia, University of Colorado, and University of Arizona, 1979-1980 (Box 49, Folder 28)
  - "Meaning of Probability", undated (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - "Modern Conceptions of Space", undated (Box 50, Folder 2)